Hi, my name is Ksenia and today I will
tell you what's new in Business Central
2026 Wave 2 for the master data
management. So,
uh I guess lots of you already used our
master data management between companies
in the same environment. So, you know
that we already can synchronize data
between headquarter and other companies,
but it happened only inside the same
environment. Lots of customers has a
different story and they need to use
multiple environments in the same
tenant. For example, per country, per
brand, or in other cases.
In that scenario, unfortunately, before
now they had no chance to synchronize
data with the standard functionality, so
they needed to find another way, maybe
retype it manually, do some other
integration, whatever. And of course,
it's not comfortable and cause lots of
errors.
So, what is new? Now, it will be
possible for subsidiaries in the same
tenant, but different environments to
pull data from the HQ company. And it is
a fully built-in solution, so no
middleware, no custom code, no extra
service.
It's built-in.
And
another plus, it is completely the same
UI experience,
similar setup, which you already knows.
Let's see a bit on the picture, so it's
more visual. You can see on the left
side, it is HQ
and
it can give an access to the
subsidiaries, so they can pull data from
HQ. HQ still the read-only and the main
source uh of the data.
Uh we can see the data will cross the
environment boundary and the access will
be through the Microsoft Entra ID.
Uh so, all subsidiaries can pull the
data, and they're not every time getting
all the things, but only the changes.
Behind it is a technology we're using or
data before web service, and also, as I
mentioned, it will go with the Entra ID.
So,
company will need to register an app in
the Microsoft Entra.
Then,
uh HQ admin will need to approve, give a
constant in BC. So, HQ always can decide
which subsidiaries are going to read and
what they're going to read. So, you need
to remember when you're adding tables,
HQ need to give the read permissions.
Uh so, the subsidiary will have an
access to them.
Uh also, pictures and attachments will
travel along with the record. The only,
for now, limitation there, pictures,
uh
should be up to 512 KB each, no more.
So, as you already understand, all the
environments should be in the same
tenant,
but
different environments are allowed.
Uh same mapping, same synchronization
engine. So, only the setup for the app
itself,
uh for subsidiaries, it will be quite
easy. Uh they will have a wizard where
they will need to type the credentials,
and credentials will keep
uh kept very secure, so no one will be
able just to read them in any moment.
So, that's also quite good. Also,
customer can decide if they want to
register one app and share it between
multiple subsidiaries, or if they want
to register
app for each.
So, depends on your audit path, you can
make that decision.
Uh now, I want to give a word to our
engineer, George. He will show how it
works.
>> Uh hello, my name is George and I will
walk you through how synchronization of
data
across environment works in Business
Central. So, here I am in a empty
company that has no customers, vendors,
or other master data.
Uh it's in this environment that doesn't
have CD a suffix.
Uh and here I have another environment.
This is my headquarters or the source
environment where I'm pulling data from.
So, just to show you that this this is a
different environment. It has the CD
suffix.
So, let's see how would we go about
doing this in the subsidiary company.
Just to show you how this is set up.
I have master data management set up and
we have added a few more actions and one
of them is cross environment set up.
It opens up a wizard in which you
consent to the privacy notice.
And I have already entered the
environment name of my headquarters and
the company name uh where I will be
pulling data from and the client ID and
client secret of the OAuth 2 app that I
registered.
Where is that app? That app should be
registered in the same tenant. You can
do it in Azure portal.
And here you we will document all this,
but just to show you that uh
the app needs to have this
API read write all application level
permissions.
And it should have this redirect URL.
We will document all this and it should
have a single single tenant sign in
audience.
So, um I entered the um
the credentials of this app.
And in the source environment,
here we are in the source environment.
Microsoft Entra applications,
the admin needs to consent this app
uh and allow it to access
uh the data.
And crucially, when the user for this
app is created, uh there will be an
Entra user.
Uh then the admin should assign
this specific um permission set that we
designed. It's off the page and it
includes the the rights to execute this
logic. And it includes read permissions
for all the default tables. As Xenia
mentioned, if you add more tables than
the default ones,
then you need to
create a new permission set and add read
permissions to these tables to this
Entra user in the source. So, this way
the admin has control of who reads what.
Let's go back in the subsidiary.
So, when you set this up and enable the
data synchronization,
the typical flow like for same
environment the synchronization is to
start initial synchronization.
Here you see all the all the default
tables that we have. And for the initial
synchronization, uh you click the start
all
and it goes in a certain order. It It
asks you whether you want to proceed.
Just like for the same environment
uh case, it goes in a predefined order.
First, business relation table, then
dimension, and so on and so on.
This uh takes some time. So, you can uh
you can keep refreshing to see the the
status.
So, now we can see that initial
synchronization is completed.
And we can go back to our starting page
and refresh it.
And we can see that we have our
customers here in the subsidiary. They
have synchronized from the source
environment. You have also vendors and
all the default master data records.
Now, let me demonstrate how the the the
changes in the source propagate to the
subsidiary. Let's change a customer that
is synchronized.
Change its name.
And after about a minute
in the in the source environment, we
should see the change. While we're
waiting for that, I can show you that
I'm in the UI for managing the the
synchronization is the same as for one
single environment synchronization. You
go to synchronization tables, and let's
see for the customer table, I can I can
look up my synchronization log. This is
the crucial page.
And I can see that one modified. It's
because it changed in the source.
And if I
refresh, I can see it got the new value
that was
changed in the source. So, the
rescheduling of synchronization jobs and
the automatic change propagation works
uh seamlessly.
That's it for our demo. So, you can
synchronize data across environments
now.
Thank you for watching.